

Muhammad Bilal Sulaimankhil

POWERCODERS PARTICIPANT

PROFILE

A person with strong motivation and having more than three years of experience as a receptionist with special skills in communication, learning and solving problems.

A true team player with collaboration skills and a mindset that always strives to find best practice development, now seeking a career switch position in the IT area.

IT SKILLS

★★★☆☆ INTERMEDIATE

★☆☆☆ BEGINNER

HTML, CSS, Figma, Github, **MS Office** JAVASCRIPT, SCSS, Bootstrap

CONTACT & PERSONAL



bilal.sulaimankhil@powercoders.org



+41 76 442 64 84



Müllheimerstrasse 143, 4057, Basel



LinkedIn-Link GitHub-Link

Afghan, Permit (F) 03.12.1994

WORK EXPERIENCE

03.2021 - 06.2021

	•
08.2020 - 12.2020 Kitchen help in th	ne deaconess house, Riehen Basel
05.2020 - 07.2020 Internship in Afghand online seller,	nan Oriental grocery store Mini Market Birsfelden Basel
05.2019 - 11.2019 On the Way through	gh Turkey, Greece, France ,Switzerland
03.2018 - 04.2019 Receptionist at Bl Turkey	lue Moon Cave Hotel ,Kapadokya, Nevsehir,
06.2017 - 02.2018 Agricultural Worke Sellers, Center, Tu	ers, Aytekin Manav Supermarket and Online rkey
2015 - 2016 Retail employee, s Afghanistan	service, checkout, Supermarket Kabul,
·	AKIHE Ghazi Amanullah Khan Institute of , Kabul, Afghanistan
2013 - 2014 Taxi driver, self-er	mployed, Kabul, Afghanistan

Employees in the Brockenhaus, Brockino Basel

LANGUAGES

PASHTO / DARI MOTHER TONGUE

FARSI C2
ENGLISH B2
TURKISH B2
GERMAN B2
URDU B1

EDUCATION

09.2022 - 12.2022

POWERCODERS - CODING ACADEMY FOR REFUGEES, BERN

- Foundations in HTML, CSS, JavaScript; specialization tracks upcoming
- Weekly business & social skills training (team work, communication, etc.)

CERTIFICATES - Switzerland

05.2022 – 07.2022 Preparatory IT Course in HiCoders, Zürich, Switzerland 04.2022 – 06.2022 Web Development course HTML, CSS in Swisscom, Bern,

Switzerland

01.2020-07.2022 German Language from start up to B2 Telc in Academia Basel

Switzerland

REFERENCES

HANY WASSEF, LEAD COMPANY RELATIONS DCH

hany.wassef@powercoders.org,

+41 77 992 84 58

CONTINUOUS EDUCATION (Language and IT Courses)

Improving English and German Language in Academia Basel, Switzerland Online IT Skills in Kiron

HOBBIES

Playing Chess Reading Philosophy books Dancing Salsa in Salsa flow Club Basel Hiking and Climbing in the Alp's and Jungfrau mountains.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

In Turkey, I was a free interpreter for patients and people who had language problems in the hospital and immigration office for 6 months.